Thomas Thompson Trust Records, 1844-2001
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- SERIES III. FINANCIAL RECORDS 1901-69
  - Ledger sheets
    - Requisitions and expenses, 1925-61, undated (Box 25, Folder 1-14)
    - Requisitions and expenses, 1926-42 (Box 26, Folder 1-2)
  - Balance sheets, 1925-74 (Box 26, Folder 3-6)
  - Trial balances, 1962 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Cash receipts and disbursements
    - 1961-63 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - 1964-67 (Box 27, Folder 1-3)
    - Florence Wells, 1962-63 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Adaline Shea, 1964-65 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Five-year audits, 1930-40 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Yearly audit reports
    - Thomas Thompson Trust
      - 1931-59 (Box 27, Folder 7-9)
      - 1960-70 (Box 28, Folder 1-2)
    - Brattleboro Mutual Aid Association
      - 1944-65 (Box 28, Folder 3-6)
      - 1966-73 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Ledger books, 1902-73 (Box 30)
  - Brattleboro
    - Check registers
      - 1916-30 (Box 31)
      - 11 Oct. 1930-1 Oct. 1938 (Box 32)
      - 1 Oct. 1938-Sept. 1955 (Box 33)
      - Oct. 1955-Apr. 1965 (Box 34)
  - Rhinebeck
    - Check registers, 1946-69 (Box 34)
    - Cash and ledger, 1947-69 (Box 34)
      [See also SERIES IX. OVERSIZE MATERIAL for: Earnings statements, 1930-43]
- SERIES IV. LEGAL RECORDS 1844-1946
  - Thomas Thompson's last will and testament, 1869 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Legal interpretations of the Thompson will, undated (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Probate Court--trustee appointments, 1911-46 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Notices, 1904-20, undated (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Brattleboro Memorial Hospital, 1904 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Client-related documents, 1923-1935 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Client mortgages, 1855-1923 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Townsend Place
    - Deeds and lease agreements, 1842-41 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1911-29 (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Repair and maintenance contracts, 1915-17, undated (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Plot plan, 1844 (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - General legal documents, 1901-44 (Box 35, Folder 12-14)
  - Court cases
    - 1907-08
      - Correspondence (Box 35, Folder 15)
      - Client affidavits (Box 35, Folder 16)
      - Petitions and decrees (Box 35, Folder 17)
    - Mulvey case, 1917 (Box 35, Folder 18)
    - 1919-20
      - Correspondence (Box 36, Folder 1)
      - Petitions, decrees, and statements (Box 36, Folder 2)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 36, Folder 3)
- SERIES V. AGENCIES/SERVICE PROGRAMS 1907-77
  - Brattleboro Mutual Aid Association
    - Administration
      - Histories
        - 1935-46, undated (Box 36, Folder 4)
        - Drafts, undated (Box 36, Folder 5)
      - Anniversaries, 1928, 1947, 1956-57 (Box 36, Folder 6)
      - By-laws, 1908, 1926, 1952, undated (Box 36, Folder 7)
      - Members, 1945-47, undated (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - Minutes
        - Executive Board, 1939-51, undated (Box 36, Folder 9)
        - 1907-11 (Box 36, Folder 10)
        - with attachments, 1928-46 (Box 36, Folder 11-13)
      - Secretary's records, 1942-46 (Box 36, Folder 14)
      - Personnel, 1951, undated (Box 36, Folder 15)
      - Press releases, 1952, 1958, undated (Box 36, Folder 16)
      - Thompson House disaster plans, circa 1982 (Box 36, Folder 17)
    - Financial
      - Client expenditures, 1907-09 (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - Clients, 1912-13 (Box 37, Folder 2)
      - Reports, 1907-47, undated (Box 37, Folder 3)
      - Requisitions, 1920-33 (Box 37, Folder 4)
      - Reduction plan, 1931-32 (Box 37, Folder 5)
      - Stock receipts, 1943-73 (Box 37, Folder 6)
      - Monthly Treasurer's reports, 1921-63 (Box 37, Folder 7-13)
    - Florence Wells
      - Notes and drafts, undated (Box 37, Folder 14)
      - Speeches (Box 37, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1931-70 (Box 38, Folder 1-3)
      - Bradley, Richards M., 1939-42 (Box 38, Folder 4)
      - Burtek case, 1973-76 (Box 38, Folder 5)
      - Re: clients, 1964-67 (Box 38, Folder 6)
      - Fawcett, Benjamin, 1973-75 (Box 38, Folder 7)
      - Harris Place
        - General, 1917-25 (Box 38, Folder 8)
        - Legal documents, 1924-25 (Box 38, Folder 9)
      - National Organization for Public Health Nursing, 1919 (Box 38, Folder 10)
      - Wells, Florence H., 1939 (Box 38, Folder 11)
      - Re: Florence Wells, 1962-63 (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - Programs
      - Children's Repair Fund, 1939-43 (Box 38, Folder 13)
      - Cooperation with Hospital, undated (Box 38, Folder 14)
      - Dental hygiene
        - Report and proposal, 1916, undated (Box 38, Folder 15)
        - Annual reports, 1936-42 (Box 38, Folder 16)
        - Monthly reports
          - 1937-39 (Box 38, Folder 17-19)
          - 1940-42 (Box 39, Folder 1-3)
        - Genevieve M. Ely, "The Importance of Baby Teeth": speech, undated (Box 39, Folder 4)
      - Federal Nutritional Survey Unit, 1945 (Box 39, Folder 5)
      - Health exhibit, 1910 (Box 39, Folder 6)
      - House tour, 1954-58 (Box 39, Folder 7)
      - Influenza epidemic, 1920 (Box 39, Folder 8)
      - Nursing Center, undated (Box 39, Folder 9)
      - Preschool clinic, 1923, 1938 (Box 39, Folder 10)
      - Public health (District) nursing
        - General, 1917-52, undated (Box 39, Folder 11)
        - Instructive District Nursing Association (Boston), 1920-24 (Box 39, Folder 12)
        - National Organization for Public Health Nursing, 1942-50, undated (Box 39, Folder 13)
      - Red Cross, 1917-35, undated (Box 39, Folder 14)
      - School nurse, 1916-37, undated (Box 39, Folder 15)
      - Services to the sick, 1921-28 (Box 39, Folder 16)
      - Special Children's Health Fund, 1941-44 (Box 39, Folder 17)
      - Thompson School for Practical Nursing
        - History, undated (Box 39, Folder 18)
        - Correspondence, 1950-51 (Box 39, Folder 19)
        - Applications for Director, 1950-51 (Box 39, Folder 20)
        - Nurses' training publications (Box 39, Folder 21)
        - Radio script, undated (Box 39, Folder 22)
        - Reports, 1950, undated (Box 39, Folder 23)
        - National Association for Practical Nurse Education
          - Accreditation, 1949-51 (Box 39, Folder 24)
          - Constitution and By-laws, 1947, 1951 (Box 39, Folder 25)
          - Newsletters, 1949-50, undated (Box 39, Folder 26)
          - Conference, 1948-50 (Box 39, Folder 27)
          - Speech, 1949 (Box 39, Folder 28)
          - Pamphlets, undated (Box 39, Folder 29)
        - Publications not by Thompson School, 1912-50, undated (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Tuberculosis Camp, 1911, undated (Box 40, Folder 2)
      - Tuberculosis exhibit, 1909 (Box 40, Folder 3)
      - "Typical Day," 1910, 1915 (Box 40, Folder 4)
      - Vacation house
        - Property, 1912, 1936 (Box 40, Folder 5)
        - Applicants, 1914-21 (Box 40, Folder 6-13)
    - Reports
      - Attendant Nursing Service, 1939-42 (Box 40, Folder 14)
      - Attendant Nursing Statistics, 1934-35 (Box 40, Folder 15)
      - Auxiliary Services, 1959 (Box 40, Folder 16)
      - Comparison of Practical Nursing Schools, undated, circa 1940s (Box 40, Folder 17)
      - Public health (district) nurses, 1939-42, 1945, 1951 (Box 40, Folder 18-19)
      - Rural nurse, 1930-37, 1939 (Box 40, Folder 20)
      - Supervisor, 1928-29, 1944-46, 1949-50 (Box 40, Folder 21)
      - Sub-committees, 1938-59 (Box 40, Folder 22)
      - Miscellaneous, 1917, undated (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - Fragments, undated (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Annual reports
      - Drafts, 1949, 1956 (Box 41, Folder 3)
      - Typescripts, 1945-58 (Box 41, Folder 4)
      - Published, 1920-48 (Box 41, Folder 5-6)
    - Publications
      - "The Brattleboro Mutual Aid Association" undated, circa 1910s (Box 41, Folder 7)
      - "Hospital Benefit Service," undated, circa 1933 (Box 41, Folder 8)
      - "Health and Service System," 1931 (Box 41, Folder 9)
      - "Health Work in Windham County," 1931 (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Brattleboro Memorial Hospital
    - History
      - Pamphlets, 1926, 1954-58 (Box 41, Folder 11)
      - Suggestions from doctors, 1901 (Box 41, Folder 12)
      - Information re: other hospitals, circa 1901 (Box 41, Folder 13)
      - Richards M. Bradley, "A Well Ordered Hospital": speech, undated, circa 1901 (Box 41, Folder 14)
      - Construction, 1903-04 (Box 41, Folder 15)
      - Plan of land near hospital, undated (Box 41, Folder 16)
      - Hospital charter, 1904, 1953 (Box 41, Folder 17)
      - Hospital notice, 1910 (Box 41, Folder 18)
      - Patient survey, undated (Box 41, Folder 19)
      - Hospital supply catalogs, undated, circa 1940s (Box 41, Folder 20)
      - Administrative reports, 1912-14, undated (Box 41, Folder 21)
      - Annual reports, 1906, 1908-13 (Box 41, Folder 22-23)
    - Financial
      - Funding, 1930-42 (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Sources of income, 1934-35 (Box 42, Folder 2)
      - Client payments, 1901-18 (Box 42, Folder 3)
      - Schedule of fees, 1924 (Box 42, Folder 4)
      - Accountants' reports, 1907-08 (Box 42, Folder 5)
      - Yearly audits, 1933-37, 1942 (Box 42, Folder 6-7)
      - Monthly expense reports, January 1935-February 1943 (Box 42, Folder 8-11)
    - Graduate Nurses
      - Legislation, 1911, 1941 (Box 42, Folder 12)
      - Reports
        - Miscellaneous, 1912, undated, circa 1930s (Box 42, Folder 13)
        - National League of Nursing Education, 1934 (Box 42, Folder 14)
      - Questionnaire, 1942 (Box 42, Folder 15)
  - Rhinebeck
    - Expenses, 1901-20 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1903, 1922, 1929, undated (Box 43, Folder 2)
      - Greenough, Dorothy
        - Harding and Koch, 1947-51 (Box 43, Folder 3)
        - General, 1947-63 (Box 43, Folder 4-6)
      - Hudson, Miriam, 1939-43, 1946-47 (Box 43, Folder 7-8)
      - Miller, George N., M.D., 1925-32 (Box 43, Folder 9-13)
      - Trustees, 1941-43 (Box 43, Folder 14)
    - Minutes, 1913, 1929 (Box 43, Folder 15)
    - Reports
      - Agency for Dependent Children, 1916-17 (Box 43, Folder 16)
      - Client case reports, 1914-17 (Box 43, Folder 17)
      - Legislation, 1934-36 (Box 44, Folder 1)
      - Nurses' monthly reports, 1919 (Box 44, Folder 2)
      - Special reports, 1914-19, 1931, 1939-43, undated (Box 44, Folder 3)
      - Superintendent's reports, 1918, undated (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Research notes, 1910-13 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Publications, 1908, 1915, 1931, 1936, 1947, 1953, undated (Box 44, Folder 6-7)
    - Programs
      - Dutchess County Health Association
        - Proposal, 1922 (Box 44, Folder 8)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 44, Folder 9)
      - North Dutchess County Nursing Service
        - Financial reports, 1938-44 (Box 44, Folder 10)
        - Correspondence, 1938-42 (Box 44, Folder 11)
        - Monthly reports, 1919, 1933-34, 1939-44 (Box 44, Folder 12-13)
        - Annual reports, 1939-43 (Box 44, Folder 14)
        - General, undated (Box 44, Folder 14a)
        - Therapeutic abortions: correspondence, 1938 (Box 44, Folder 15)
        - Registry, 1939-41 (Box 44, Folder 16)
        - Reports, 1940-42 (Box 44, Folder 17)
        - Publications, undated (Box 44, Folder 18)
      - Thompson House
        - Financial
          - Accountants' report, 1903-08 (Box 44, Folder 19)
          - Treasurer's reports, 1916-43 (Box 45, Folder 1-2)
          - Audits, 1919-42 (Box 45, Folder 3-4)
          - Expenditures, 1911-18 (Box 45, Folder 5)
        - Proposal, undated (Box 45, Folder 6)
        - Construction expenses, 1907-10 (Box 45, Folder 7)
        - Monthly reports, 1916-21 (Box 45, Folder 8)
        - Reports, 1915, 1941-42 (Box 45, Folder 9)
        - Annual report, 1915 (Box 45, Folder 10)
- SERIES VI. INSURANCE PROGRAMS--Thompson Benefit Associations 1926-59
  - General
    - Survey, 1941 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Reports, undated (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Drafts and notes, undated (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Publications, 1926-32 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Financial, 1931-33, 1946, undated (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Thompson Benefit Association for Nursing Service
    - Publications, 1926-42 (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - Client payments, 1926-56 (Box 46, Folder 7-17)
  - Brattleboro Memorial Hospital Benefit Association
    - Premiums collected, 1933-35 (Box 46, Folder 18)
    - Total hospital charges, 1934-35 (Box 46, Folder 19)
    - Non-Surgical case insurance, 1934-35 (Box 46, Folder 20)
    - Northfield student service, 1934-37 (Box 46, Folder 21-22)
    - Mr. Grimshaw's reports, 1935-36 (Box 46, Folder 23)
    - Miss Converse's reports, 1938-39 (Box 46, Folder 24)
    - Publications, 1930s (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Reports, 1936, 1941 (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Annual reports, 1937-43 (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Financial
      - Client accounts, 1933, 1946 (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - Infirmary payments, 1938-46 (Box 47, Folder 5)
      - Infirmary receipts, 1945-46 (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Legal: Freeman case, 1932-33 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Springfield (VT) Mutual Benefit Association, 1937-42 (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Publications re: other insurance plans, 1910s-1950s (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Insurance client records
    - Ledger sheets, 1932-33 (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - Ledger sheets, 1945-60 (Box 47, Folder 11-12)
    - Premium cards, 1920s-50s (Box 48-50)
    - Disbursements, 1920s-50s; Information, 1920s (Box 51)
    - Enrollment, 1920s-30s (Box 52-53)
    - Receipts, 1930s-50s (Box 54-56)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 57)
- SERIES VII. CLIENT RECORDS 1901-69
  - Report to Committee for Working Women Under Thompson Will, A-Z, 1901-05 (Box 58)
  - Interview re: vital statistics, A-Y, 1901-09 (Box 59, Folder 1-4)
  - Applications for aid, 1914-19 (Box 59, Folder 5)
  - Case Files (numerical)
    - #1501-1563 (Box 60, Folder 1-40)
    - #1564-1695 (Box 61, Folder 1-34)
    - 1705-1760 (Box 62, Folder 1-46)
    - 1761-1860 (Box 63, Folder 1-60)
    - 1861-2499 (Box 64, Folder 1-37)
    - #2516-2694 (Box 65, Folder 1-68)
  - Case files (alphabetical)-Brattleboro
    - A-Ber (Box 66, Folder 1-34)
    - Bet-C (Box 67, Folder 1-47)
    - D-F (Box 68, Folder 1-35)
    - D-F (Box 68a, Folder 36-50)
    - G-H (Box 69, Folder 1-36)
    - I-L (Box 70, Folder 1-27)
    - M (Box 71, Folder 1-21)
    - N-O (Box 72, Folder 1-12)
    - P-Sh (Box 73, Folder 1-29)
    - Sm-V (Box 74, Folder 1-29)
    - W-Y, no name (Box 75, Folder 1-21)
  - Case files (alphabetical)-Rhinebeck
    - A-B (Box 76, Folder 1-13)
    - C-L (Box 77, Folder 1-18)
    - M-V (Box 78, Folder 1-25)
    - W (Box 79, Folder 1-6)
  - Case files (chronological)-Rhinebeck
    - 1947-52 (Box 80, Folder 1-37)
    - 1949-55 (Box 81, Folder 1-30)
    - 1949-55 (Box 82, Folder 1-31)
    - 1955-62 (Box 83, Folder 1-28)
    - Rhinebeck, A-Z, 1960-69 (Box 84-85, Folder 1-24)
  - Wells, Florence
    - Correspondence, 1927-60 (Box 86, Folder 1-4)
    - "Notes," undated (Box 86, Folder 5-7)
    - Massachusetts Eye and Ear, 1928-32 (Box 87, Folder 1)
  - Physicians
    - Reports, 1924, 1931, 1936 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - Patient charges, 1936-43 (Box 87, Folder 3-5)
    - Minimum charges, 1940 (Box 87, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1940-1951 (Box 87, Folder 7-9)
  - Client loans
    - Brattleboro, 1914-17, 1924, 1926, 1932 (Box 87, Folder 10)
    - Rhinebeck, 1904-41 (Box 88, Folder 1)
  - Client reports
    - Brattleboro, 1902-03, 1909 (Box 88, Folder 2-3)
    - Rhinebeck, 1906 (Box 88, Folder 4)
    - Sample cases, 1909 (Box 88, Folder 5)
    - Miss Davis' reports, 1914 (Box 88, Folder 6)
    - Patients admitted to BMH, undated (Box 88, Folder 7)
    - Client expenditures, Brattleboro, 1913-49 (Box 88, Folder 8-11)
    - Client payments, Brattleboro, 1901-07, 1917-19, 1947 (Box 88, Folder 12-13)
    - Client receipts, A-Z (Box 89-96)
- SERIES VIII. PHOTOGRAPHS/SCRAPBOOKS 1902-62, undated
  - Photographs, 1910s-40s, undated (Box 97)
  - Scrapbooks, 1902-64, 1980 (Box 98-105)
- SERIES IX. OVERSIZE MATERIALS 1901-2001
  - Architectural drawings
    - Brattleboro Hospital (Map-case Flat File)
    - Brattleboro Hospital, alterations and additions (Map-case Flat File)
    - Portable cottage (Map-case Flat File)
    - Sewage disposal (Map-case Flat File)
  - Expenditure sheets, 1901-30 (Map-case Flat File)
  - Estate of Thomas Thompson: statements of earnings, 1930-1943 (Map-case Flat File)
  - Disease Classifications: charts (Map-case Flat File)
  - Notice of Centennial Celebration in Brattleboro, Vermont: poster, Dec. 13-15, 2001 (Map-case Flat File)